<dashboard version="1.1" theme="light" script="tabs.js" stylesheet="tabs.css">
  <label>Introduction to EDI Transmission &amp; Acknowledgment Monitoring</label>
  <description>Use Case - Monitoring EDI Transactions  |  Monitoring EDI Transmission and Acknowledgment</description>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
            <h1>
               <img width="40" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_target.png"/>
               <b>INTRODUCTION</b> 
            </h1>
            <ul>
            <p>Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) is the electronic exchange of business documents between companies, using standardized formats. EDI plays a critical role in ensuring that data flows seamlessly across various stakeholders—suppliers, manufacturers, logistics providers, and retailers—without manual intervention. It is a core technology for automating supply chain processes, enabling organizations to quickly and securely exchange important documents such as purchase orders (850), invoices (810), shipment notifications (856), and functional acknowledgments (997) between systems. This automation helps reduce errors, speed up processes, and improve the overall efficiency of the supply chain.</p>
            <p>In understanding electronic data interchange (EDI), the proper exchange and acknowledgment of EDI messages between suppliers, manufacturers, and customers are crucial for ensuring smooth supply chain operations. When an EDI message is sent, the receiving system must respond with an acknowledgment, confirming that the transmission was successful and the document has been recognized. Additionally, monitoring the acknowledgment process (for example, receiving 997 functional acknowledgments) confirms that the recipient successfully received the transmitted EDI documents. Failures or delays in these transmissions can disrupt procurement, inventory management, and fulfillment processes, leading to operational delays, stock shortages, or delayed payments. All of this ultimately impacts both operational efficiency and customer satisfaction.</p>
            <p>By continuously monitoring EDI transmissions and acknowledgments, businesses can proactively identify and resolve issues, ensuring smooth communication between systems and uninterrupted supply chain operations.</p>
               </ul>
         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tabs">
    <panel>
      <html>
            <p>
            <ul id="tabs" class="nav nav-tabs">
               <li> <img width="200" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_navi_gr_button.png"/>
            </li>
               <li class="active">
              <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_objective">1 | OBJECTIVE</a>
            </li>
               <li>
              <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_method">2 | KPIs</a>
            </li>
               <li>
              <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_step_00,tab_step_00_01,tab_step_00_02,tab_step_00_03,tab_step_00_04,tab_step_00_05,tab_title_01,tab_step_01,tab_title_02,tab_step_02,tab_title_03,tab_step_03,tab_title_04,tab_step_04_01,tab_title_05,tab_step_05,tab_title_05,tab_step_06,tab_step_07,tab_step_08,tab_step_09,tab_step_10">3 | ACCESS DATA</a>
               </li>
               <li>
              <a href="https://lantern.splunk.com/Splunk_Platform/UCE/Manufacturing/Monitoring_EDI_transmission_and_acknowledgement" target="_blank">4 | LANTERN RECIPES</a>
            </li>
            </ul>
            </p>
         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tab_objective">
    <panel>
      <html>
            <ul>
               <h1>
                  <img width="35" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_target.png"/>
                  <b>OBJECTIVE :</b> 
               </h1>
               <p>Successful transmission and acknowledgment of EDI documents are crucial to maintaining an efficient supply chain. When an EDI document, such as a Purchase Order (EDI 850), is sent, it must be delivered to the intended recipient and acknowledged to confirm receipt. A key part of this process is the functional acknowledgment (EDI 997), which serves as a receipt that confirms whether the document has been successfully received and processed by the trading partner’s system.</p>
               <p>Several types of EDI documents are commonly used throughout the supply chain, each serving a specific function : 
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li>
                        <b>Purchase Orders (EDI 850)</b> : Used to place orders with suppliers.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>Order Acknowledgments (EDI 855)</b> : Confirm that the supplier has received the purchase order.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>Advance Ship Notices (EDI 856)</b> : Provide details about shipments that are en route.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>Invoices (EDI 810)</b> : Outline the billing details for the goods or services provided
                     </li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
               </p> 
               <p>The 997 Functional Acknowledgment confirms that these documents have been received and processed successfully. Without receiving these acknowledgments, businesses are left in the dark about whether critical documents have been delivered, risking delays in order fulfillment, inventory management, and payment processing.</p>
            </ul>
            <hr width="100%"/>
            <ul>
               <h1>
                  <img width="35" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_target.png"/>
                  <b>PREREQUISITES :</b> 
               </h1>
               <p>The following software is required for this use case :</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li>
                        <b>The Splunk platform</b> : Mainly used for initial data processing, analysis and alerting.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>Splunk ITSI</b> (Optional) : For futher expanding the analytics leveraging ITSI's thresholding and anomaly detection capability.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>SAP PowerConnect</b> (Optional) : If the supply chain operational transactions needs to be integrated from SAP ERP. this is nessasary.
                     </li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
               <p>The following data types from supply chain operational transactions are required inputs for accomplishing this use case :</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li>
                        <b>EDI X12, EDIFACT</b> : Standard supply chain transations data.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>API Data</b> (Optional) : Supply chain transations data gathered through APIs.
                     </li>
                     <li>
                        <b>SAP iDocs</b> (Optional) : iDocs data collected using SAP Powerconnect for Splunk.
                     </li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
            </ul>
         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tab_method">
    <panel>
      <html>
            <ul>
               <h1>
                  <img width="35" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_target.png"/>
                  <b>KPIs : What to monitor?</b> 
               </h1>
               <p>It's important to track a few key performance indicators (KPIs) to ensure EDI messages are processed correctly. </p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li>
                <b>Monitoring Acknowledgments</b> : Track the receipt of acknowledgment documents (997) within a specified time frame after sending each transaction.</li>
                     <li>
                <b>Transmission Success Rates</b> : Ensure EDI documents such as POs (850), ASNs (856), and Invoices (810) are successfully transmitted to their respective recipients.</li>
                     <li>
                <b>Transmission Errors and Retry Rates</b> : Look for EDI documents that fail to transmit or are stuck in retry loops. Lost or failed EDI transactions can lead to operational inefficiencies, such as missed orders, delayed shipments, or inventory discrepancies.</li>
                     <li>
                <b>Acknowledgment Timing</b> : Monitor delayed acknowledgments.</li>
                     <li>
                <b>Finding Repeated Failure Patterns</b> : Look for patterns of repeated transmission or acknowledgment errors might indicate a systemic issue.</li>
               </ul>
               <p>Delays or failures in transmitting or receiving EDI documents can cause significant disruptions in the supply chain, leading to procurement delays, missed deliveries, and potential financial penalties.</p>
               <p>Click on the link to the above KPIs to directly navigate to the analysis.</p>

            </ul>  </ul>

         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tab_step_00">
    <panel>
      <html tokens="true">
            <ul>
               <h1>
                  <img width="35" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_tool.png"/>
                  <b>ACCESS DATA : Data cube for Purchase order lifecycle monitoring</b> 
               </h1>
               <p>To begin building the base data cube, calculate key performance indicators (KPIs) to monitor EDI transmission and acknowledgment, which are crucial for assessing the health of your EDI transaction systems. These KPIs can also help identify potential infrastructure issues that may hinder your organization’s ability to process critical EDI information across your supply chain partners.</p>
            </ul>
         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tab_step_01">
    <panel>
      <table>
        <title>RESULT ANALYSIS 01 : EDI Transactions with response status determined.</title>
        <search>
          <query>sourcetype="edi:x12" 
| table _time edi_ack_status edi_buyer edi_code edi_code_ack edi_cont_num edi_date edi_flag edi_requestor edi_responder edi_seller edi_sequence edi_time edi_tr_id edi_type 
| eval edi_ack_status_combo=edi_code+"-"+edi_code_ack+"-"+edi_ack_status
| eval edi_code_groupby=if(isnull(edi_code_ack), edi_code, edi_code_ack)
| stats last(_time) AS _time, last(edi_requestor) AS edi_requestor, last(edi_responder) AS edi_responder, first(edi_code) AS edi_type, values(edi_code) AS edi_code, last(edi_ack_status) AS edi_ack_status BY edi_tr_id edi_code_groupby</query>
          <earliest>-7d@h</earliest>
          <latest>now</latest>
          <sampleRatio>1</sampleRatio>
        </search>
        <option name="count">15</option>
        <option name="drilldown">none</option>
        <option name="refresh.display">progressbar</option>
        <format type="color" field="edi_ack_status">
          <colorPalette type="map">{"Not Received":#3C444D,"R":#E3723A,"E":#D41F1F}</colorPalette>
        </format>
      </table>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row id="tab_next">
    <panel>
      <html tokens="true">
            <ul>
               <h1>
                  <img width="45" src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/PM_image_icon_ques.png"/>
                  <b>Do you need help? Ask an Manufacturing and IoT Expert.</b>
               </h1>
               <p>
                 Need help with your environment or requirements? Send us your questions, and we’ll get back to you as soon as possible.
                  <ul>
                     <li> For detailed step-by-step instructions on implementing the solution using this Solutions Accelerator, visit our <a href="https://lantern.splunk.com/@go/page/6494">
                  <b>Solutions Accelerator</b>
                </a> page.</li>
                     <li> To expedite implementation with professional services, please reach out to our sales team by clicking <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/ask-an-expert.html?expertCode=supply_chain_solutions_accelerator" target="_ask_expert">
                  <b>Contact Us</b>
                </a>
              </li>
                     <li> If you need immediate assistance, explore our community forum, <a href="http://answers.splunk.com/">
                  <b>Splunk Answers</b>
                </a>.</li>
                  </ul>
               </p>
               <img src="/static/app/supply_chain_edi/SI_image_bullet_03.png"/> <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/ask-an-expert.html?expertCode=supply_chain_solutions_accelerator" class="btn" target="_ask_expert">Contact Us</a>
            </ul>
        
         </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>
