<dashboard version="1.1" theme="light" script="tabs.js" stylesheet="tabs.css">
   <label>Introduction</label>
   <row>
      <panel>
         <html>
            <img width="1200" usemap="#nav_banner_map" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/SA_OT_Sec_banner_01.png"/>
            <map name="nav_banner_map">
               <area shape="rect" coords="40,365,172,400" alt="demo" target="_show_demo" href="/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/industrial_port_usage"/>
            </map>
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/SI_image_icon_07.png"/>
               WELCOME TO SPLUNK OT SECURITY SOLUTIONS ACCELERATOR : <font color="#8B0000">OT Security</font>
            </h1>
            <p>
               Explore the new <b>OT Security Solutions Accelerator</b> to access a variety of solution components designed to jump-start your journey to securing your OT environemtn. Use the <b>navigation tab</b> to find documentation, use cases, and ready-to-use examples.
            </p>
 
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tabs">
      <panel>
         <html>
            <ul id="tabs" class="nav nav-tabs">
               <li> <img width="200" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_navi_gr_button.png"/>
               </li>
               <li class="active">
                  <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_01"> <font color="#8B0000">1 | INTRODUCTION</font></a>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_02"><font color="#8B0000">2 | WHY SPLUNK?</font></a>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_03"><font color="#8B0000">3 | WHAT'S IN THE APP</font></a>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_04"><font color="#8B0000">4 | REFERENCE ARCHITECTURE</font></a>
               </li>
               <li>
                  <a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_05"><font color="#8B0000">5 | REQUIREMENTS</font></a>
               </li>

               <!--li><a href="#" class="toggle-tab" data-toggle="tab" data-elements="tab_next">WHAT'S NEXT?</a></li-->
            </ul>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_01">
      <panel>
         <html>
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_target.png"/>
               <b>INTRODUCTION</b> 
            </h1>
            <ul>
               <p>The goal of the OT Security Solution Accelerator is more than just providing dashboards and content within Splunk Enterprise and Splunk Cloud.  The overall goal is to help organizations better understand how to address specific use cases and challenges when dealing with an OT environment. This includes providing customers information regarding:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b>Reference architectures</b> :  Designed to help you understand how other organizations today deploy Splunk in various scenarios such as air gapped environments, hybrid, or even cloud scenarios</li>
                     <li><b>Data management</b> : This data management content provides guidance around how to get data into Splunk with and without agents, based on real customer experience and dealing with OT environment limitations.</li>
                     <li><b>Install Guide and Configuration Guide</b> : These guides help you understand how to deploy this app and additional configuration needed to use the existing dashboards are populating..</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
               <p>The Solution Accelerator is designed to help you get started with Splunk Enterprise and Splunk Cloud.  For a more complete and integrated solution with Splunk Enterprise Security it is recommended you leverage the OT Security Add-on for Splunk or contact your sales team for more information.</p>
               </ul>
               
               <hr/>
               <h2>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_bulb.png"/>
                  <b>HELPFUL RESOURCES</b> 
               </h2>
               <ul>
               <ul>
               <h2>
                  <b>Splunk Lantern for Industries</b> 
               </h2>
               <p>Let Splunk experts light your path toward gaining valuable data insights, achieving your key use cases, and managing Splunk more efficiently.</p>
               <p>Our official product documentation will help you understand how to generally set up alerts and dashboards, but it won't connect that information to specific data types and vertical specific use cases.</p>
               <p>That's where Lantern comes in - by providing information that's written by Splunk experts, is applicable across different types of environments, and is oriented towards your industries specific goals, you get the step-by-step guidance you need to plug into your deployment and start working toward your business use cases right away.</p>
               <p>The Lantern Use Case Explorer for the Splunk Platform is designed to help inspire as you develop new use cases using either Splunk Enterprise or Splunk Cloud Platform and will guide you to know how to implement use cases specific to your industry, no matter where you are in your data journey.</p>
               <h2>
                  <b>Splunk for Manufacturing</b> 
               </h2>
               <p>See how Splunk can help you solve all kinds of data challenges. Explore how to enhance IT/OT Security, achieve foundational visibility across IT and OT systems, enable enhanced business process and service monitoring, and build next-gen operations on Splunk.</p>
               </ul>
            </ul>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_02">
      <panel>
         <html>
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_bulb.png"/>
               WHY SPLUNK ? 
            </h1>
            <ul>
               <p>
                 Many OT environments are compromised of multiple OT vendor solutions which follow different practices when logging data.  Also the need to monitor underlying infrastructure is crucial to protecting the complete OT environment.  Leveraging Splunk allows you to ingest this diverse and well-known data into a single system and then apply structure at readtime.  This same data can then be leveraged for operation and system use cases, helping organizations achieve better resilence.  
               </p>
               <p>The advantages of using Splunk for OT Security are:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b>Scalability</b> :  From mebabytes to pedabytes, Splunk is designed to scale for large and small data loads as needed.  Splunk in OT can be deployed as a single instance to distributed high availablity clusters.</li>
                     <li><b>Quick value</b> :  Splunk's ability to ingest structured and unstructure data provides an advatange with the diverse forms of data encountered within OT environments.  This allows organizations to begin using their OT data without worrying about schematizing the data beforehand.  Data is accessible immediately upon ingest.</li>
                     <li><b>Flexibility</b> :  Splunk's ability to ingest data from air-gapped, shared, hybrid, or cloud environments helps organizations deploy Splunk in the manner they need to.  In addition, Splunk can collect data via agent and agentless methods allow it to meet vendors requirements without compromising safety or security.</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
          </ul>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_03">
      <panel>
         <html tokens="true">
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_bulb.png"/>
               <b>WHAT'S IN THE APP :</b> 
            </h1>
            <ul>
               <p> This app includes two main components detailed below:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b>Use Cases</b> :  This sections includes detailed information on base searches and examples within the app. This content can also be found in the IT/OT Security section on <a href="https://lantern.splunk.com/Splunk_Platform/UCE/Manufacturing">Lantern for Manufacturing</a></li>
                     <li><b>Examples</b> :  The examples included contain content that can be used in production that implement the use cases.  In each case, the same base searches used in the use case section are leveraged in these examples.</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
          </ul>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_04">
      <panel>
         <html tokens="true">
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_bulb.png"/>
               <b>REFERENCE ARCHITECTURE :</b> 
            </h1>
            <ul>
               <p>Deployment of Splunk within an OT environment needs to accomodate various different scenarios.  This includes different architectures and methods to collect data from OT assets.  The following resources are available to help answer your questions:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b><a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/blob/main/OT%20Security/Documentation/Data%20Management.md">Data Management Guide</a></b> :  This guide provides detailed information on how customers collect data in OT environments with and without agents.</li>
                     <li><b><a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/blob/main/OT%20Security/Reference%20Architecture/Splunk%20Arch%20-%20OT%20and%20IT%20Isoldated%20On%20Premise.pdf">OT and IT Isolated Instances of Splunk</a></b> :  Architecture for scenarios where Splunk may be deployed on premise in a dedicated OT Splunk instance</li>
                     <li><b><a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/blob/main/OT%20Security/Reference%20Architecture/Splunk%20Arch%20-%20Shared%20IT%3AOT%20On%20Premise.pdf">Shared IT/OT On Premise Instances of Splunk</a></b> :  Architecture of a unified IT/OT instances of Splunk kept on premise</li>
                     <li><b><a href="Splunk Arch - OT On Premise and IT in Cloud.pdf">OT On Premise and IT in Cloud Instances of Splunk</a></b> :  Architecture of a instance where the OT instance of Splunk remains on premise and IT leverages Splunk in the Cloud (also known as hybrid)</li>
                     <li><b><a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/blob/main/OT%20Security/Reference%20Architecture/Splunk%20Arch%20-%20OT%20in%20Cloud.pdf">OT in Cloud Instances of Splunk</a></b> :  Architecture of how to get data to a cloud instance of Splunk</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
          </ul>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_05">
      <panel>
         <html tokens="true">
            <h1>
               <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_bulb.png"/>
               <b>REQUIREMENTS :</b> 
            </h1>
            <ul>
              <h2><b>CONFIGURATION GUIDES</b></h2>
               <p> The following knowledge objects must be configured in order for dashboards and reports to populate:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b>Eventtypes</b> :  Eventtypes are used to tag data so that base searches know what data to search.</li>
                     <li><b>Macros</b> :  Macros allow a user to filter data that is used across the app.</li>
                     <li><b>Lookups</b> :  Lookups are used to identify industrial data protocols within network and firewall traffic.</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
               <p></p><p>For more detailed guide see the <a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/blob/main/OT%20Security/Documentation/Configuration%20Guide.md">Configuration Guide</a> on the <a href="https://github.com/splunk/MFG-SOLN-ACCELERATORS/tree/main/OT%20Security">OT Security Solution Accelerator</a> on github</p>
              <h2><b>DATA SOURCES</b></h2>
               <p> The use cases and examples here make use of the following data sources:</p>
               <ul>
                  <ul>
                     <li><b>Network Traffic</b> :  Network traffic is used to identify access attempts to assets such as remote access hosts and to identify industrial protocol traffic.</li>
                     <li><b>Firewall Traffic</b> :  Firewall traffic is used for the Perimeter Security use cases where ingress and egress traffic is analyzed.</li>
                     <li><b>Windows Registry Events</b> :  Windows registry events contain information on the use of external media devices such as USB drive.</li>
                  </ul>
               </ul>
          </ul>
          </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
   <row id="tab_next">
      <panel>
         <html tokens="true">
               <h1>
                  <img width="45" src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/PM_image_icon_ques.png"/>
                  <b>Do you need help? Ask an Manufacturing and IoT Expert.</b>
               </h1>
            <ul>

               <p>
                  Need help with your environment or requirements? Send us your questions, and we’ll get back to you as soon as possible.

               <ul>
                  <li> For detailed step-by-step instructions on implementing the solution using this Solutions Accelerator, visit our <a href="https://lantern.splunk.com/@go/page/6494"><b>Solutions Accelerator</b></a> page.</li>
                  <li> To expedite implementation with professional services, please reach out to our sales team by clicking <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/ask-an-expert.html?expertCode=ot_security" target="_ask_expert"><b>Contact Us</b></a></li>
                  <li> If you need immediate assistance, explore our community forum, <a href="http://answers.splunk.com/"><b>Splunk Answers</b></a>.</li>
               </ul>
               </p>
               <img src="/static/app/ot_security_soln_accelerator/SI_image_bullet_03.png"/> <a href="https://www.splunk.com/en_us/ask-an-expert.html?expertCode=ot_security" class="btn" target="_ask_expert">Contact Us</a>

            </ul>
            <table>
               <tr>
                  <td>
                     <div class="col-sm-6 col-lg-5 col-lg-offset-1 col-md-offset-1 photo-box">
                        
                     </div>
                  </td>
               </tr>
            </table>
         </html>
      </panel>
   </row>
</dashboard>
